hi guys today we're going to look at how
we can convert an existing project
using the built-in render pipeline over
to the newer universal render pipeline
urp is a scriptable render pipeline that
lets you create
optimized graphics across a wide range
of platforms it also allows us to create
shaders and effects visually
using shader graph and visual effect
graph
as always if you prefer written
instructions you can find a link to the
text version in the description
if you find this tutorial useful please
don't forget to click like and subscribe
right we're going to start with the
project we created in our slow motion
video
the first thing we need to do is import
the universal render pipeline package
to do this we'll go to window package
manager
we'll search for universal rp
and we'll install this package
now we've installed the package we need
to configure it to do this we need to
create a scriptable render pipeline
asset
by clicking the plus button on the
project panel and selecting rendering
universal render pipeline pipeline asset
asset allows us to set the graphics
quality for our game
for example we can change the shadow
quality and the anti-aliasing
this doesn't affect anything in our game
yet as we need to update our graphics
settings first
we'll go to edit project settings
we'll select the graphics tab and then
we'll drag the asset we just created
into the scriptable render pipeline
settings
you'll notice our scene is now a bit
pink to fix this
we need to convert our shaders to urp
shaders
to do this we'll select edit render
pipeline universal render pipeline
upgrade project materials to urp
materials
that's it our project is now using the
universal render pipeline
and if we change the quality settings we
can see it change in our scene
okay that covers everything for this
tutorial hope you found it useful
please leave any questions or feedback
in the comments and don't forget to
subscribe so you don't miss the next one
thanks guys
you